Guide to the Samuel DuBois Cook Papers, 1949-2015 RL.11747
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Samuel DuBois Cook Papers
1949-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cook, Samuel DuBois, 1928-2017
RL.11747
16.9 Linear Feet
Dr. Samuel DuBois Cook (1928-2017) was a political scientist who became Duke University's first African American professor in 1966. He also served as president of Dillard University from 1975 to 1997. The Samuel DuBois Cook Papers contains Cook's speech files, drafts and copies of Cook's writings, and other assorted papers including correspondence and subject folders for his research and writings on Benjamin Elijah Mays. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into series: 1. General Papers. 2. Writings. 3. Speeches.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Samuel DuBois Cook (1928-2017) was a political scientist and professor who taught at Southern University, Atlanta University, the University of Illinois, UCLA, and Duke University, where in 1966, he became the first African American professor to hold a regular faculty appointment at a predominantly white college or university in the South. In 1975 he left Duke to became president of Dillard University, serving 22 years until his retirement in 1997. He also served as a member of the Duke University Board of Trustees from 1981 to 1993.
Additional information on the life of Samuel DuBois Cook can be found online at Duke University's Samuel DuBois Cook Center for Social Equity website: https://socialequity.duke.edu/about-samuel-dubois-cook
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Samuel DuBois Cook Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018 and 2019.
Collection Overview
The Samuel DuBois Cook Papers contains Cook's speech files, drafts and copies of Cook's writings, and other assorted papers including correspondence and subject folders for his research and writings on Benjamin Elijah Mays. The correspondence is scattered but dates as early as 1949 and includes some exchanges between Cook and Duke University contacts and administration, written during his tenure as professor in the political science department. Later correspondence discusses Dillard University administration, as well as other personal and professional exchanges. Cook's research on Benjamin E. Mays includes files from his editing of the volume "Benjamin E. Mays: His Life, Contribution, and Legacy," published in 2009, as well as other drafts and files collected by Cook about Mays' writings and philosophy. Cook's other writings include drafts compiled for his Ford Foundation appointment researching desegregation and racism in the 1970s; writings and essays about Reinhold Niebuhr, Martin Luther King Jr., and historically black colleges; and his reflections on black power and the strategies of the civil rights movement. The bulk of the collection consists of Cook's speeches, filed into Dillard University and Professional Speeches subseries and arranged alphabetically by topic or title of the speech. Many of these are administrative, including many introductions of various Dillard speakers or other remarks delivered by Cook as Dillard University president.
African Americans -- Civil rights -- History -- 20th century; Segregation -- United States -- History; African American universities and colleges; Racism -- United States -- History; Black power -- History -- 20th century; African American political scientists; Mays, Benjamin Elijah, 1895-1984; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Duke University -- Faculty -- History; Morehouse College (Atlanta, Ga.); Dillard University; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture; Cook, Samuel DuBois, 1928-2017
- General Papers, 1949-2009; 1
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969, 1971-1977, 1979-2003; 37 folders (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Assorted incoming and outgoing correspondence from across Cook's personal and professional contacts. Materials have been sorted into loose chronological order, by year, but content ranges from professional commitments and responsibilities to Duke University and Dillard University; personal letters to friends and network contacts. Folders for 1967, 1972, 1976 all have letters from Benjamin E. Mays.
  - Correspondence, 1949-2009; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Cards, invitations, announcements, 1990s-2000s; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Cooks' trip to Paris, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Dillard University inauguration, 1976 (Box 1)
    Programs, events, etc.
  - Harvard University Black College Conference, 1976 (Box 1)
  - President Ford's visit to Dillard, 1977 (Box 1)
    Clippings, invitations
  - New Orleans Mayor's Charter Revision Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    Includes drafts by Cook
  - Dillard grant from Lilly Endowment, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Morehouse Research Institute program re: Benjamin E. Mays, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Black-Jewish Relations: Cook's edited volume publication packet, 1997 (Box 1)
  - General Board of Higher Education and Ministry: Council of Presidents meetings, 1997-2000; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Meeting books.
  - Atlanta Technical Institute subject file, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Church of the Good Shepherd, Chicago, Illinois, subject file, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Morehouse College/"Morehouse Man" subject file, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Ohio State University Office of Minority Affairs Young Scholars program materials, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Cook, 1960s-2000s (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Duke University, 1960s-2000s (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Dillard University, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1978-2007 (Box 13)
  - Dillard University events, programs, printed materials, 1970s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Samuel DuBois Cook awards, certificates, 1960s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Collected programs, events, and brochures, 1963-2000s (Box 1)
    Includes a range of materials from activities attended by Cook, including church services, conferences, programs, and exhibits
  - Writings by others, saved by Cook, 1987-1999 and undated (Box 2)
  - Personal documents, 1970s, 1990s (Box 2)
    Includes birth certificate (reproduction/photocopy); portrait and photographs of Cook; resume; biographical sketch
  - Dinner program, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Justice and Leadership--Role of Historically Black Universities and Colleges Conference Schedule, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Writings by others, saved by Cook, 1997 (Box 13)
- Writings, 1960s-2000s; 2
  The Writings series includes conference papers and other articles by Cook; his research on Benjamin E. Mays, former president of Morehouse College; and a set of articles by others, edited by Cook, celebrating Mays. These articles were published in 2009 as "Benjamin E. Mays: His Life, Contributions, and Legacy". Articles and essays by Cook discuss black education, the civil rights movement, black power, and desegregation; he also writes about the lives and legacies of Benjamin E. Mays and Reinhold Niebuhr.
  - Benjamin E. Mays Festschrist, 1
    - Cook: Benjamin E. Mays: Rebel, Dream, Emancipator, Prophet, and Impossible Reality (Box 2)
    - Cook: Justice and Social Change in the Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr, with Special Reference to the Contemporary Scene (Box 2)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: In My Life and Time (Box 2)
    - Zinn, Howard: American Liberalism, Source of Negro Radicalism (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Prince: Selected Aspects of Race Relations in the United States and a Psychoanalytic Dialectic: A Prolegomenon (Box 2)
    - Williams, Samuel: The Social Thought of Benjamin Elijah Mays (Box 2)
    - Wesley, Charles: A Glance at the Educational Philosophy of Benjamin E. Mays (Box 2)
    - Watters, Pat: A Change of the Mind of the (White) South (Box 2)
    - Tobin, Lucius Miles: Man's Current Predicament and the Religious and Ethical Thought of Benjamin E. Mays (Box 2)
    - Spitz, David: Power and Non-Violent Resistance: Thrasymachus and the Politics of Civil Disobedience (Box 2)
    - Smith, Frank E.: Liberal Leadership in the Present-Day South (Box 2)
    - McGill, Ralph: We are All Climbing Jacob's Ladder (Box 2)
    - Kelsey, George: Theological Analysis and Criticism of Racism in the Thought of Benjamin E. Mays (Box 2)
    - Lincoln, C. Eric: The Black Ghetto as an Urban Phenomenon (Box 2)
    - Long, Herman H.: The Higher Education of Negroes: A Forward Look (Box 2)
    - Bennett, Lerone: What Manner of Man: Benjamin Elijah Mays (Box 2)
    - Franklin, John Hope: The Roots of Dignity and Self-Respect (Box 2)
    - Thurman, Howard: Desegregation, Integration, and the Beloved Community (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Vivian: Negro Workers and the Impact of Technological Change Implications for Public Policy (Box 2)
  - Articles and Essays by Cook, 2
    - The Black Man and the American Political System: Obligation and Resistance, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
    - Black Power, White Power, and the Beloved Community, approximately 1970 (Box 3)
    - Black Voters and the Republican Record, Appeal, and Opportunity, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Book review: Antislavery: The Crusade for Freedom in America, 1966 (Box 13)
    - The Church and Human Rights, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Crisis of the Value of Personality and Community, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Democracy and the Christian Realism of Reinhold Niebuhr, undated (Box 3)
    - Dillard University Proposal for Afro/Jewish/American Informance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - On Dillard's Great Progress, but Deep Sadness and Disappointment over Alumni Giving, undated (Box 3)
    - Do We Really Believe in the Value and Dignity of the Human Person? Duke sermon, 1970 (Box 3)
    - From Subject and Victim to Citizen and Public Official: An Historical Sketch of the Negro in Southern Political Process, 1968 (Box 3)
    - The Great Breakthrough (notes/drafts re: voting rights), 1965 (Box 3)
    - Higher Education and Black Liberation, undated (Box 3)
    - Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) in the Old South and New South: Change and Continuity, undated (Box 3)
    - In Pursuit of Justice, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Is Martin Luther King, Jr., Irrelevant?, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Is the South the Land of New Opportunity for Blacks?, undated (Box 3)
    - Justice and Social Change in the Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr, with special reference to the contemporary scene, undated (Box 3)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr.: Man of Character, Thought, and Action, undated (Box 3)
    - The Negro Revolution: From Hope to Despair, approximately 1968 (Box 3)
    - Niebuhr/Martin Luther King Jr. drafts, undated (Box 3)
    - Oppressed Minorities in the American Political System and Social Order, undated (Box 3)
    - Person, Citizen, and Southern Tradition: A Problem of Justice and Being, undated (Box 3)
    - Political Dimensions of Black Liberation, undated (Box 3)
    - Political Theory and Protestant Doctrines of Original Sin: Human Nature and Forms of Government, undated (Box 3)
    - Promises to Keep: compiled speeches from Cook's Dillard presidency appointment, 1975 (Box 3)
    - A Proposal for Improving Student Performance on Standardized Tests, 1978 (Box 3)
      Dillard proposal with Elton C. Harrison.
    - Race and Ethnic Status in the South: Change and Continuity, approximately 1970 (Box 3)
    - Race and Politics (drafts, mutilated), undated (Box 3)
    - Reflections on Martin Luther King, Jr., undated (Box 3)
    - Reflections and Perspectives on Negro Institutions of Higher Education, 1965 April 25 (Box 3)
    - Time is Running Out for Racial Justice, undated (Box 3)
    - Tyranny over the Mind of the White South: An Overview of the Black Man in the Southern Political Process, undated (Box 3)
    - Where do we Go from Here? The Struggle for Racial Justice, undated (Box 3)
    - Who and What will Honor and Memorialize MLK?, 1968 (Box 3)
    - The Wisdom de Profundis of Benjamin E. Mays, Black Higher Education, and the Good Life, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Untitled draft pages, excerpts, other fragments (unsorted), undated (Box 3)
  - Benjamin E. Mays biography research files, 3
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: The President's Page (Morehouse publications by Mays), 1944-1966 (Box 4)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: "Higher Education and the American Negro," What Black Educators are Saying (photocopy), 1970 (Box 4)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: "The Role of the Schools in a Social Revolution," Teachers College Record, 1964 May (Box 4)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: "The Relevance of Mordecai Wyatt Johnson for our Times," Howard University, 1978 Jan. 27 (Box 4)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.: "Desegregate and Integrate to What End?" Founder's Day Address, Livingstone College, 1964 Feb. 11 (Box 4)
      Inscribed to Cook
    - Cook's notes, collected quotes and subject files re: Mays, 1980s-1990s; 12 folders (Box 4)
      Filed by topic. Topics include: Chapel, Morehouse, Spirituality, "Free Minds in a Segregated Society," philosophy of social change, faculty, academic and intellectual freedom, Fund for Theological Education, Mays' funeral/obituaries. Files include Cook's notes/drafts as well as clippings and other collected subject matter.
    - Clippings about Mays and his legacy, 2000s (Box 4)
    - Mays profiles, publications, obituaries, 2000s (Box 4)
    - Collected reminiscences about Mays, 2000s (Box 4)
    - Mays' excerpts and clippings of his writings/speeches, 1960s-1970s (Box 4)
    - Mays biography drafts by Cook, 1971; 2 folders (Box 4)
      Cook's original drafts and introduction to Mays' biography
- Speeches, 1974-2002; 3
  Cook and his staff kept thorough speech files for different events and programs, largely dating between 1975 and 2000. The Speeches Series has been sorted into Dillard and non-Dillard Professional Speeches -- these divisions are based on whether Cook was presenting or officiating a program on behalf of Dillard University, (usually during his presidency), or whether he attended and spoke as a private citizen or scholar, outside of his official appointment as Dillard president. Speech folders have been arranged alphabetically, by type of speech or title of the speech. Files occasionally include multiple versions or drafts, accompanying material or programs from the event, or other logistical information about Cook's participation in the occasion.
  - Dillard Speeches, 4
    - Academic Excellence, 1974-1976, undated; 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Achievement Week, 1975 Nov 9 (Box 5)
      "Promises to Keep: Rho Phi Chapter of Omega"
    - Alumni Association, 1975 May 19 (Box 5)
      "On Leadership"
    - Alumni Banquet, 1975-1996; 19 folders (Box 5)
    - Distinguished Alumni Award, 1978-1996; 20 folders (Box 5)
      Honorees Include: Emily Davis Bickham, Judge Ortique, John Louis Wilson, Lillian Dunn Perry, Ernest W. Armstrong, Dorothy Jacques Perrault, Dr. Samuel L. Biggers Jr., Henry Lucas Jr., Millie McClelland Charles, Dr. Morris Burrell, Willie Mae Crews, Dr. Anthony James Hackett Jr., Cynthia Butler-Blucher, Margaret Ferguson Washington, Gloria Humphrey Scott, Bishop Alfred L. Norris, Ralph S. Laster, Authur H, Robertson Sr., Hilda Ybonne Lincoln
    - Alumni Commendation, 1982-1985; 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Alumni Luncheon, 1984 May 12 (Box 5)
    - Alumni Vesper Service, 1975-1989; 11 folders (Box 5)
    - Annual Alumni Awards Luncheon, 1994 Apr 30 (Box 5)
      "Where Do We Go From Here?"
    - Are We Our Choices?, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Are You Willing to Pay the Price?, 1975 Nov 13 (Box 5)
    - Always Aim High, 1991 May 9 (Box 5)
      CAP Awards Program
    - American Political Science Association' Summer Institute for Black Students, 1987 Jul 13 (Box 5)
      "Reflections on My Career as a Political Scientist"
    - Athletic Banquet, 1980-1997; 13 folders (Box 5)
    - Baccalaureate, 1975-1996; 37 folders (Box 5)
      Speakers Include: Rev. Dr. Otis Moss Jr., Dr. Howard Thurman, Bishop Roy C. Nichols, Dr. Samuel Dewitt Proctor, Dr. Howard Thurman, Dr. Martin Luther King Sr., Dr. Charles G. Adams, Bishop W. T. Handy Jr., Dr. Elliott James Mason, Bishop W. Kenneth Goodson, Bishop John Hurst Adams, Dr. Zan Wesley Holmes, Bishop Leontine T. C. Kelly, Dr. Roger W. Ireson,
    - Bach Tricentennial, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 5)
      Performed by Herman D. Taylor
    - Banquet of the Division of Nursing, 1992 Apr 11 (Box 5)
      50th Anniversary
    - Black-Jewish Alliance, 1989,1997; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Black-Jewish Relations, 1988-1997, undated; 25 folders (Box 5)
    - Black History Month, 1997 Feb 20 (Box 5)
      African-Americans and the Civil Rights Movement: A Reappraisal"
    - Black Pessimism and White Optimism, 1976 Aug 2 (Box 5)
      "Black Representation in the American Political System: A Philosophical and Historical Overview"
    - Black Recognition Day Award Banquet, 1981, 1983; 2 folders (Box 5)
      "Greetings and Welcome"
    - Board of Higher Education, 1991-1996; 10 folders (Box 6)
    - Breakfast for Japanese Delegation from Matsue, 1992 Oct 30 (Box 6)
    - Brocksbank, Robert W., Luncheon, 1979 May 2 (Box 6)
      "A Man Named Bob Brocksbank and the Gift of Self"
    - Boule Meeting, 1981 Dec 20 (Box 6)
      "Ladies Night"
    - Boule Meeting, 1984 Oct 25 (Box 6)
    - Board of Trustees, 1978-1997; 33 folders (Box 6)
    - Capital Funds Campaign and Opportunities for Alumni, 1983, undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Construction of a new Fine Arts and Communications Center
    - Carter-Mondale Rally, 1980 Oct 13 (Box 6)
    - Charge to the Graduates, 1975-1996 (Box 13)
    - Clark, Kenneth B., undated (Box 6)
    - Clark, Peter W. "Champ", 1988 Nov 9 (Box 6)
      "Introductions: From Dreams to Reality"
    - College of Bishops, 1993 Jan 7 (Box 6)
      "Dillard University: Update", South Central Jurisdiction of the United Methodist Church
    - College Day, 1978 Feb 16 (Box 6)
      "Welcome to Dillard"
    - The College Fund/ UNCF and Dillard University, 1996 Nov 10 (Box 6)
      "African-American and Jews: A Dialogue about American Pluralism"
    - The College President, 1977 Jun 29 (Box 6)
      "Molder of Values or Shaped by Circumstances?"
    - Commencement, 1975-1997; 74 folders (Box 6)
      Honorees Include: Dr. Benjamin E. Mays, Dr. Lerone Bennett, Vernon Eulion Jordan, Albert Walter Dent, David Spitz, Samuel Dewitt Proctor, Coretta Scott King, Judge Robert Frederick, Dr. John Hope Franklin, Robert Frederick Collins, Dr. Benjamin Lawson Hooks, Dr. Howard Thurman, Rosa Freeman Keller, Martin Luther King Sr., Terry Stanford, Mayor Andre J. Young Jr., Mitchell Wright Spellman, Joseph Nathaniel Webster Gayles Jr., Dr. Julius S. Scott Jr., Charles Gilchrist Adams, Shirley Anita St. Hill Chisholm, Jerry Harrison Coleman, Dr. Joseph E. Lowery, John Louis Wilson, Vice President George Bush, Dr. Robert E. Johnson, Dr. Lou Rawls, Marian Wright Edelman, Ellis Louis Marsalis Jr., John Hurst Adams, William Talbot Handy Jr., Dr. Gardner Calvin Taylor, Rhetaugh Graves Dumas, Dr. Williams Wallace Sutton, Dr. Eugene C. Patterson, Bishop Leontine T. C. Kelly, Dr. Zan Wesley Holmes Jr., Dr. Millie M. Charles, Dr. Calvin O. Butts III, Dr. Roger William Ireson, Dr. Wiley Abron Perdue, Dr. Louis Westerfield, Dr. Ruth J. Simmons, Dr. Nannerl Overholser Keohane,
    - Commencement, 1975-1993 (Box 7)
      "Charge to the Graduating Seniors"
    - Conditional Congratulations, 1976 Mar 16 (Box 7)
      Delivered on Honors and Awards Day
    - Congratulations: Teachers of the Year, 1993 Mar 23 (Box 7)
      University Assembly Honoring Dillard Alumni Chosen "Teachers of the Year"
    - Convocation-Freshman, 1975-1995; 17 folders (Box 7)
    - Convocation-University, 1975-1996; 28 folders (Box 7)
    - Cook, Samuel DuBois, undated (Box 7)
      "Message from the President of the University"
    - Council of Presidents, 1997 Sep 19 (Box 7)
      "Tributes to Mrs. Julius S. Scott Jr. and Mrs. Oscar A. Rogers Jr."
    - Dargan, Rita E. Miller, 1983 Apr 12 (Box 7)
      "In Gratitude"
    - Dargan, Rita E. Miller, 1983 Apr 15 (Box 7)
      "Presentation of Presidential Distinguished Achievement Award"
    - Dedications, 1974-1995, undated; 9 folders (Box 7)
      Dedications Include: Study Lounge in Camphor Hall, Young Sr. Faculty Center, Thelma R. and Sidney N. Collier Conference Center, Alumni Dedication of Land
    - Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc., 1980 Mar 2 (Box 7)
      Delivered at the Ebony Exhibit and Reception
    - Democracy and Tyranny in America, undated (Box 7)
      "The Radical Paradox of the Bicentennial and Blacks in the American Political System"
    - Dent, Albert Walter, 1977 May 16 (Box 7)
      Doctor of Humane Letters
    - Dent, Albert Walter, 1984 Feb 15 (Box 7)
      "Words of Reflection"
    - Dent, Albert Walter, 1985 Jun 7 (Box 7)
      "Endowed Scholarship Fund" Delivered at Executive Committee Meeting
    - Dent, Albert Walter, 1992 Sep 13 (Box 7)
      Reception Honoring the Late Dr. Albert W. Dent on the Occasion of the Dedication of a Lupin Family Foundation Grant
    - Dillard Club Meeting, 1976 Apr 29 (Box 7)
      "Academic Excellence: Dillard's Supreme Goal
    - Dillard Day, 1976-1996, undated; 12 folders (Box 7)
    - Dillard's Great Progress, undated (Box 7)
      Dillard's Great Progress, But Deep Sadness and Disappointment over Alumni Giving
    - Dillard University, 1976-1985; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Dillard/Xavier Council Luncheon, 1974-1982; 9 folders (Box 7)
    - Dinners, 1986, 1995; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Annual Christmas Dinner, Dinner in Honor of Dr. Ruth J. Simmons
    - Dissemination Conference, 1984 Apr 27 (Box 7)
    - Distinguished Achievement Award, 1985-1988; 3 folders (Box 7)
      Honorees Include: Dr. Samuel P Massie, Dr. Robert E. Johnson, Dr. William E. Nelson Jr.
    - Distinguished American Award, 1989 Apr 26 (Box 7)
      National Football Hall of Fame Distinguished American Award
    - District Conference, 1978 May 7 (Box 7)
      "The Church, Its Institutions, and the Kingdom Not of This World"
    - Disturbed About Man, undated (Box 7)
      Dr. Mays on the Tragedy of Life
    - Edwards, Dr. Benjamin G., 1993 Apr 27 (Box 7)
      "Meeting with Dr. Benjamin G. Edwards"
    - Education Day at Dillard, 1995 Mar 21 (Box 7)
    - Enthusiasm and Self-Sacrifice, 1976 Apr 7 (Box 7)
      Delivered at a Luncheon in Honor of Bishop Finis A. Crutchfield
    - Epps, Harold Joseph, 1981 Jan 16 (Box 7)
      Delivered on the Occasion of the Retirement Luncheon
    - EOD Awards and Presentation, 1981 Dec 18 (Box 7)
    - Establishment of the Japanese Studies Program, 1990 Aug 15 (Box 7)
      Press Conference
    - Executive Committee Meeting, 1985 Sep 9 (Box 7)
    - Farewell, 1996 Oct 19 (Box 7)
      "Of Time Change, and Retirement: Farewell From A Grateful Heart"
    - Flint-Goodridge Hospital, 1983 Feb 1 (Box 7)
      "The Sale of Flint-Goodridge Hospital of Dillard University: An Overview"
    - Ford, President Gerald, 1977 Nov 17 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Conference, 1984 Aug 16 (Box 7)
    - The Faculty and Our "Promises to Keep", 1975 Feb 6 (Box 7)
    - Founders' Day, 1975-1991; 26 folders (Box 7)
      Speakers Include: Andrew Jackson Young Jr., Dr. Elliott James Mason, Dr. James R. Buck, Dr. Williams Holmes Borders Sr., Dr. Charles Shelby Rooks, Dr. George Washington Calvin Sr., Dr. David E. Chambers, Dr. Julius S. Scott Jr., Dr. Alfred L. Norris, James Samuel Thomas, Dr. Joyce Marie Roche
    - Founders' Day, 1992-1996; 11 folders (Box 8)
      Speakers Include: Harold Wayne Lundy, Johnny Ray Youngblood, Dr. Harry Straks Wright, Dr. Cornelius L. Henderson, Bishop W. T. Handy, Charles Austin Ferguson, Lester Elliot Karbacoff, Revius Oliver Ortique Jr.
    - Gayles, Joseph N. Webster, 1983 May 16 (Box 8)
      Doctor of Laws
    - The Gift of Self, 1975 Dec 19 (Box 8)
      Delivered at a Luncheon in Honor of Dr. and Mrs. Frederick D. Hall and Dr. Ulysses S. Saucedo
    - Gillespie, Charles A. Jr., 1984 Nov 14 (Box 8)